Mitchell Thomas

Senior Software Engineer

Stamford, Connecticut linkedin.com/in/mitchellthecoder github.com/mitthoma mitthoma@gmail.com (917) 974-6786

Over my 6-year professional development and engineering career, I have played the role of software architect, lead engineer and contributing engineer as well as handled project management and client interaction on 30+ projects. I have touched multiple areas of emerging technologies and development, including full-stack web development, blockchain engineering, and Al engineering.

Work Experience

Full Stack Developer

Open Health Scientific Communications

Dec 2021 - Current

- Architected and developed a suite of applications within the Hive ecosystem, contributing approximately \$2 million in annual revenue from around 15+ major biotech clients.
- Led the design and implementation of a no-code email management feature, enabling users to dynamically utilise application data to create and schedule multiple email templates and triggers per end user and is integrated with thousands of events daily.
- Designed and implemented a monolithic multi-tenant system, consolidating client server instances and reducing server costs by 80-90%, while supporting multiple product connections and maintaining data separation and security.

Co-Founder, Senior Full Stack **Blacsand** Software Engineer

Jul 2019 - Current

- Developed and launched a chiropractic SaaS application, enabling users to track patient data, and chiropractic metrics with a modern UI for generating custom reports, enhancing end user clinic operations.
- Pioneered innovative frontend solutions using Vue, Vuex, Nuxt, React, Redux, HTML, and CSS, delivering cutting-edge web designs for over 22 clients, enhancing user experience across various platforms.
- Created a suite of applications for doctors to provide prescribed video content to patients, integrating iOS and Android mobile apps, APIs, and a web admin panel, including a paywall functionality expanding revenue streams.

Web Developer Vadela Jul 2018 - Jun 2019

- Constructed an interactive website for the "This Is Orlando" campaign, integrating functionality that engaged over 50,000 followers from the @orlando Instagram account, boosting online presence and community engagement.
- Collaborated effectively within a growing team of creatives, producing desirable results for multiple Vadela clients, and introduced a new offering to build and manage web applications for the agency's existing clients.
- Facilitated business development by attending in-person meetings with various Orlando businesses to discuss and tailor service offerings, fostering strong client relationships and expanding the client base.

Education

B.S. Computer Science - Artificial Intelligence Specialization

Indiana University Bloomington minor in Human Centered Computing

Aug 2015 - Dec 2019

Tech Stack

Typescript, React/Redux/Next, Vue/Vuex/Nuxt, Javascript, MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Python, Solidity, Java, HTML, CSS, Docker, AWS, Azure, Vercel, Prisma, TypeORM,

Coding Projects -

Blockchain Kickstarter

https://mt.codes

Sep 2021 - Oct 2021

- Developed smart contracts for a blockchain crowdfunding platform, enabling contributors to vote on campaign fund distributions using Solidity, Truffle, and Web3 libraries and Solidity. Built a higher level manager contract as well as a more specific contract used for transactions initiated for each campaign on the platform.
- Built a front-end website for creating and managing blockchain campaigns, facilitating user contributions and engagement using React.

COVID CNN Neural Network

https://mt.codes

Apr 2020 - May 2020

 Built a GoogLeNet convolutional neural network to classify X-ray images of lungs for COVID-19 detection, achieving an accuracy of 75-92% using 50 previously classified samples from Kaggle. Developed using Python and Tensorflow.

Notable Publications + Projects

- IPFS: The Web3 Data Storage Revolution Becoming Human: Artificial Intelligence Magazine October 2022
- Benefits Of Decentralized Cloud Storage Becoming Human: Artificial Intelligence Magazine April 2021
- Simple Example of Deploying a smart Contract (and what that means) Becoming Human: Artificial Intelligence Magazine April 2021
- Deep learning with COVID-19 xray convolutional Neural Network Becoming Human: Artificial Intelligence Magazine March 2020

https://mitchellthomas.vercel.app